welcome back to another darktable
欢迎回到另一张暗桌
tutorial in this video we're going to be
在这段视频中 我们将成为
bringing in some raw photos and editing
带来一些原始照片并进行编辑
those raw photos and developing them
那些原始照片并冲洗它们
improving them so in the last tutorial
在上一篇教程中对它们进行了改进
we kind of have these things brought in
我们把这些东西带进来了
and I just wanna show you how to kind of
我只想向你们展示如何
clean this up a little bit we can go to
把这里清理一下 我们可以去
this select box over here and we can go
这个选择框在这里 我们就可以走了
select all that I'll select everything
选择所有选项我将选择所有选项
in here and then what we can do is under
在这里 我们所能做的就是
this selected images we have all kinds
这个精选的图片我们有各种各样的
of options for things we can do to those
我们可以对这些人做的事情的选择
selected images we can like reset
我们可以重置的精选图像
rotation we can duplicate all of these
轮换我们可以复制所有这些
we can copy them if we do duplicate
如果我们复制的话 我们可以复制它们
they're all duplicated so we have a
它们都是重复的 所以我们有一个
duplicate copy of each one of these and
每一份的复印件和
now only the only every other one is
现在唯一其他的就是
selected and we can go to select all
选中 我们可以转到全选
again and we can just go to remove and
再来一次 我们可以去删除和
that will remove them from darktable I
这将把它们从暗表I中移除
believe trash will actually delete them
我相信垃圾真的会删除它们
from the computer so don't do that one
所以不要再做那个了
but anyway so now we have we're back to
但不管怎样 现在我们又回到了
the start here and I want to bring in
从这里开始 我想引入
some raw photos I want to show you I
一些我想给你看的原始照片
have a couple different ones I have some
有几个不同的 我有一些
that I shot and I have some that I
那是我拍的 我有一些
downloaded where the end so here's just
下载到哪里结束了 所以这里只是
some that I shot we can just click and I
有些是我拍的 我们只需点击一下就可以了
think I have it set up right now so that
我想我现在已经设置好了 所以
if I if I click on my raw photo it opens
如果我如果我点击我的原始照片 它会打开
it up in darktable
把它放在暗桌上
but you can also right-click and go open
但您也可以右键单击并打开
with on my particular computer and I can
在我特定的计算机上 我可以
open it raaah photos with image viewer
使用图像查看器打开它的照片
so I can just look at this picture in my
所以我可以在我的电脑里看到这张照片
image viewer your computer may be a
图像查看器您的计算机可能是
little bit different on this but these
这个有点不同 但这些
are some pictures I took just the other
是我拍的另一张照片吗
day and I made sure to shoot them with
戴和我确保用来拍摄他们
my Canon camera in raw mode so they're
我的佳能相机处于RAW模式 所以他们
this dot cr2 which is a Canon RAW format
此点CR2是佳能RAW格式
and when I opened this one up like we
当我像我们一样打开这个的时候
learned in the last video it created
从它创建的上一个视频中了解到
sort of a metadata or a dark table edit
类似于元数据或暗表编辑
file associated with it
与其关联的文件
so when we edit this picture now here in
所以当我们现在编辑这张照片的时候
dark table it's only going to apply
黑暗的桌子它只会适用于
edits not to the picture directly and
不直接对图片进行编辑
it's non-destructive editing is what
它的非破坏性编辑是什么
that's called so we had this picture
这就是所谓的 所以我们有这张照片
here we see in the light table we have
这是我们在灯光桌上看到的
just a single picture now and in the
只有一张现在和将来的照片
darkroom it brings up brings up the last
它带来的暗室带来了最后一个
tool we had in use which is this
我们正在使用的工具是这个
vignette I think is that what's going on
Vignette我认为这是正在发生的事情
here so yeah and that's under well what
在这里 是的 那是在什么下面？
we can do
我们可以做到
before we get ahead of ourselves we can
在我们超越自己之前 我们可以
come over here to see what effects are
到这里来看看有什么效果
being applied to the picture so let's
被应用到图片上 所以让我们
look at that real quick there's these
快看 这就是这些
different icons we can left-click and
我们可以左键点击和点击不同的图标
toggle between them this very first one
在它们之间切换这就是第一个
shows us like a power button icon and so
向我们展示了一个电源按钮图标 所以
this shows us which ones are enabled
这将向我们显示哪些已启用
there's a tiny little thing right here
这里有一件很小的东西
it's kind of hard to see but it shows us
它很难看到 但它向我们展示了
this is this picture is automatically
这是这张照片是自动的
being sharpened it's automatically
被磨得锋利 它是自动的
having a base curve applied the
将基础曲线应用于
orientation is automatically on
方向会自动打开
highlight reconstruction white balance
突出重建白平衡
all of these are on and enabled by
所有这些都处于启用状态 并由
default right now with this picture so
默认使用此图片 因此
we can click on white balance we can
我们可以点击白平衡 我们可以
change the temperature of this which
改变这一点的温度
will change so now we have a much
将会发生变化 所以现在我们有很多
brighter more like a yellow warm sky and
更明亮 更像一片黄色温暖的天空
then if we want to see what it looks
如果我们想看看它是什么样子
like with that not applied we can click
如果未应用该选项 我们可以单击
this button here and it will go back to
这里的这个按钮 它将返回到
how it was before anything was applied
它是什么都没有应用之前的样子
so it looks very green right now this is
所以它现在看起来很绿 这是
kind of the more raw how it was taken
更原始的是如何看待它的
and then this is with it applied so you
然后这是应用了它的 所以你
can apply and D apply or enable and
可以应用和D应用或启用和
disable any of the any of these effects
禁用其中任何一种效果
being applied just by clicking on this
只需点击此按钮即可应用
button right here another way that we
按钮就在这里 我们用另一种方式
can change and see what's happening is
可以改变并看到正在发生的事情
by going over to the history and we can
通过回顾历史 我们可以
look at the very original picture so
看看这张非常原始的照片吧
this is originally what it looked like
这是它最初看起来的样子
and then after applying sharpen it looks
然后在应用锐化之后 它看起来
like this after applying the orientation
像这样应用方向后
it looks the same because it wasn't
它看起来一样 因为它不是
rotated after applying the base curve it
在应用基础曲线后旋转
looks a little bit different here so we
这里看起来有点不同 所以我们
can see between this step here and this
可以看出在这一步和这一步之间
step here it's quite a bit different and
站在这里 它有很大的不同
then the white balance being applied is
那么正在应用的白平衡是
different as well
也不一样
highlight reconstruction not a lot of
高光重建不是很多
change there and then this a white
换成那个 然后换成白色的
balance again is being applied so this
正在再次应用平衡 因此此
shows us our history stack of all the
向我们展示了我们的历史堆栈
changes that have gone through here at
在这里经历的变化
any point if we want to we can go just
任何时候只要我们想去我们都可以去
to this base curve point and we can
到这个基本曲线点 我们可以
export it right here if we go into the
如果我们进入
light table now it appears the same way
光桌子现在看起来是一样的
that it does in darkroom I want to bring
我想把它放在暗室里
in some more photos from this photo
在这张照片中的更多照片中
shoot so I'll go over here to this
拍摄 所以我要走到这里来
folder under import and I'll just import
文件夹在导入下 我将只导入
the entire directory of all the pictures
所有图片的整个目录
shot in this photo shoot
拍摄于这张照片中
and what that does is it lets us see
它的作用是让我们看到
everything in here that was shot so I'll
这里的一切都是被枪杀的所以我会
grab like maybe this picture of these
像这样抓起这张照片
rocks right here because I want to show
就在这里 因为我想展示
you what's applied by default by dark
您在黑暗中默认应用的是什么
table we can see that by looking over
我们可以通过查看表格来看到这一点
here in the history again we can go back
在历史上 我们又一次可以回到过去
to the original so this is a little bit
到原版 所以这有一点
process that's still pretty close to raw
仍相当接近RAW的工艺
but it's still processed if we click on
但如果我们点击
original we see what the original image
原来我们看到的是什么原创图像
look like that looks like this is the
看起来这看起来像是
raw image it's kind of dull it doesn't
原始图像 有点沉闷 一点也不
have any sharpening applied doesn't have
有没有任何锐化的应用没有
the base curve applied and so we can see
应用了基本曲线 因此我们可以看到
what each step would look like and we
每一步看起来是什么样子 我们
see it's enhanced just subtly by default
请看 它在默认情况下得到了微妙的增强
by dark tables so just be aware if you
在黑暗的桌子旁 所以要知道如果你
want to work from the very very
我想从非常非常的地方开始工作
beginning you'll want to click on this
开始时 您会想要点击这个
original and start working from there
原创 并从那里开始工作
but it's a good idea this base curve is
但这条基本曲线是个好主意
really I don't understand it entirely
真的 我不是完全明白
but over here we can find the base curve
但在这里我们可以找到基本曲线
if we click on the effects that are
如果我们点击这些影响
enabled we see this base curve is a
使我们能够看到这条基本曲线是一个
cannon base curve and so we can see if
大炮的底座曲线 所以我们可以看到
it was shot with an icon we'd be able to
它是用图标拍摄的 我们可以
do like this Nikon like and it looks a
像尼康这样做 它看起来像
little different or if it wasn't like
有点不同 或者如果它不像
Panasonic or these different ones but
松下或这些不同的 但
since my camera was a Canon camera that
因为我的相机是佳能相机
actually shot this image and since that
实际上拍摄了这张照片 自从那以后
was attached to the metadata of that raw
附加到该原始数据的元数据
picture it just automatically applied
想象一下它刚刚自动应用
this and what it's doing is is giving us
这和它所做的是给我们
an accurate representation of the
一种准确的表示
lighting and the colors because it knows
灯光和颜色 因为它知道
how Canon processes pictures or creates
佳能如何处理图片或创作
RAW images how that sensor you know
原始图像你知道传感器是怎么回事
records light anyway so we want to keep
无论如何 记录都很少 所以我们想要
this the same but if we wanted to change
这是一样的 但如果我们想要改变
it we can come over here and adjust it a
如果我们可以到这里来 把它调整成
little bit and we can make changes and
一点点 我们就可以做出改变
that'll adjust this if whenever we
它会调整这个 如果我们每次
change it too much we can click this
改得太多了 我们可以点击这个
little icon here and it sets everything
这里的小图标 它设置了一切
to default in this case it's the default
在这种情况下默认 这是默认的
curve which is a straight line which
曲线是一条直线
gives us kind of how it looked back in
给了我们它在过去是什么样子的
the original but we can come over here
原件 但我们可以来这里
and again apply the Canon light curve
并再次应用佳能光线曲线
which gives us a kind of a different
这给了我们一种不同的
look I want to show you on this too we
听着 我也想让你看看我们
can do one thing like this white balance
可以做一件像这样的白平衡的事情
we can you know change the temperature
你知道 我们可以改变温度
like we did before make it a little
就像我们以前做的那样 让它有点
warmer make it a little cooler exposure
更暖和的天气让它暴露在更凉爽的环境中
if you want to find a certain thing
如果你想找到某样东西
before
在此之前
mess too much with temperature we might
我们可能会在温度上搞得太乱
want to do exposure so we can find
想要曝光这样我们就能找到
exposure it's actually one of the ones I
曝光它实际上是我
think it's over here yeah so if we click
我想它在这里 是的 所以如果我们点击
this circle here exposure is one of the
这里的这个圆圈曝光的是
options we have but we can find it from
我们有选择 但我们可以从
down below as well and then exposure we
也在下面 然后曝光我们
can just adjust if maybe we feel like
如果我们觉得
parts of this or underexposed or
这部分或曝光不足或
overexposed we can adjust it accordingly
曝光过多 我们可以相应地进行调整
and we can use this histogram up here as
我们可以在这里使用这个直方图作为
a reference to see if we're kind of
一个参考 看看我们是不是
clipping data so we're clipping a little
裁剪数据 所以我们要裁剪一些
bit of data in there and so we can
里面有一些数据 所以我们可以
adjust this to kind of make that fill
调整这个来做那个填充物
our whole area and then we kind of see
我们的整个区域 然后我们可以看到
kind of that's more bright and so we
这样就更明亮了 所以我们
adjust that similar routes this is
调整类似的路线这是
probably a good time to point out that
或许是个好时机来指出
I'm really not a photographer and I'm
我真的不是摄影师 我是
not into I'm not really experienced in
不喜欢 我在这方面没什么经验
color correcting and photo enhancing so
色彩校正和照片增强SO
I'm just trying to demonstrate darktable
我只是想证明暗桌
and show you how to use the effects but
并向你展示如何使用特效 但是
unfortunately I'm gonna be limited in
不幸的是 我将被限制在
what I'm actually able to show you from
我实际上能够向你们展示的是
an artistic or from a be what I'm saying
我要说的是艺术性的或来自于
right from that standpoint anyway I feel
不管怎么说 从这个角度来看 我觉得
like this is a good point to end this
好像这是结束这一切的好时机
video on I just want to show you down
我只是想让你失望
here at the bottom we touched a little
在这里的底部 我们触摸到了一点
bit on it but any of these things we
但这些东西中的任何一件我们
want to add we can click over here and a
想要添加我们可以点击这里和一个
star will appear and it will be then
明星将会出现 它将会出现
added to our favorites so we have a
添加到我们的收藏夹中 因此我们有一个
couple different things added to our
几个不同的东西添加到我们的
favorites if there's one that you're
最受欢迎的 如果有一个是你
using all the time you might want to
利用你可能想要的所有时间
just add it to your favorites and then
只需将其添加到您的收藏夹中 然后
quickly you'll have a nice little
很快你就会有一个漂亮的小
workflow it's a little bit daunting at
工作流程这有点让人望而生畏
first but just know that this one shows
首先 但要知道这张照片显示了
you which ones are enabled by default
您可以选择默认启用哪些选项
you can disable them and enable them and
您可以禁用和启用它们 然后
then these other ones just show you ones
然后这些其他的只会给你看
that deal more with like color you can
你可以更多地处理相似的颜色
hover over I'm going to tells you this
悬停在我要告诉你的事情上
deals with more of tone this one is your
处理更多的语气这是你的
basic group which is kind of what you
基本基团就是你想要的
it's a good idea to go through and
这是一个好主意 通过和
adjust these at first and so we're just
首先调整这些 所以我们只是
getting started I would say go through
开始吧 我想说的是通过
and play with these and just see how it
玩玩这些 看看它是如何
just your picture and you're gonna find
只有你的照片 你会发现
some things that you like to use and
一些你喜欢使用的东西和
like to not use anyway I appreciate you
不管怎样 我喜欢不用 我很感谢你
watching check out the next tutorial
观看签出下一教程
we'll be learning about snapshots and
我们将学习快照和
how to look at before and afters and
如何看待前后和
we'll play some more with some different
我们会再玩一些不同的
effects as well catch you in the next
效果也会赶上你在下一个
video
视频